Guide to the History of Education Society collection, 1960-2013 MS2341
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
History of Education Society collection
1960-2013
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
History of Education Society
MS2341
35 Linear Feet
The History of Education Society was founded in 1960 and works to promote the study of the history of education by scholars and by people who work for education policy and reform. The records in this collection tell the story of this organization through meeting minutes, financial records, conference programs, committee and Board of Trustees rosters, images, correspondence, the records of the History of Education Quarterly the HES journal. The records cover the founding in 1960 through 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
Within the records of the initial donation March 2015 and subsequent donation from October 2020 the "accepted and rejected manuscripts" submitted to the History of Education Quarterly are restricted from use for 50 years from date of donation. This is to protect the privacy of authors and peer reviewers.
All donations from HES to GW starting in May 2021, will arrive at GW with any personally identifiable information redacted. These redacted records will be available without restriction for use by the public following archival processing.
At the end of their tenure editing the History of Education Quarterly the editorial team will donate a spreadsheet that provides the list of authors, reviewers, manuscript titles, and manuscript numbers. Each spreadsheet will be restricted from use for 50 years from the date of donation.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the History of Education Society, March 12, 2015 (acc. 2015.035). Subsequent donations were made in 2020 and 2021.
Arrangement
Organized into 5 series: Annual meetings, Governance and Society records, Journal History of Education Quarterly, Religious education, and History of Education Quarterly restricted content
Organizational history
In 1948, the National Society of College Teachers of Education began a History of Education Section. The Section published the History of Education Journal. Throughout the 1950s, scholars argued over the field's aims and in 1960 the History of Education Society was founded as an independent organization, succeeding the Section. The society influenced by revisionism in the 1970s encouraged its historians to debate American public education's societal and individual roles in the society's journal and annual meetings. In 1961, the History of Education Quarterly replaced the History of Education Journal and published the society's work. The journal operated out of the University of Pittsburgh, later moved to New York University, and has subsequently been affiliated with Indiana University, Slippery Rock University, the University of Illinois and the University of Washington. In 1988, the society affiliated with the International Standing Conference for the History of Education, which hosts annual meetings for the field around the world in conjunction with regional history of education societies. The History of Education Society holds an annual conference in October, in addition, the Society also hosts several awards for scholars. From its Website From its Website the HES describes its goals as: promoting and improving the teaching of the history of education in colleges and universities, encouraging scholarly research in the history of education and facilitating the publication and dissemination of the results of this research, working to interest education professionals and the public in the value of the historical perspective when making education policy, promoting libraries and museums to preserve source materials used in the study of the history of education, encouraging the collaboration of scholars throughout the world on studies and the exchange of documents and ideas and cooperating with organizations of professional historians and professional educators throughout the world.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains meeting minutes, financial records, conference programs, reports, committee rosters, Board of Director rosters, correspondence and photographs related to the history of the organization. The material dates from 1960 through 2013.
Education
- Annual meetings, 1977-2013; Series 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged loosely alphabetically by folder title. The folders correspond with the annual meetings and are identified by the city where the meeting was held and also the year of the meeting.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains records related to the annual meetings including planning documents and publicity. The records date from 1977-2013.
  - 13th Session of the International Standing Conference for the History of Education, July 30, 1990; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Albany, 1991; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Allerton Contract, 2009; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Meetings, 1977-1990; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Atlanta, 1999; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Baltimore, 2005; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Boston, 1992; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cambridge, 2010; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chapel Hill, 1993-1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chicago, 1993; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chicago, 1997-1998; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cleveland, 2007; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Evanston, 2003-2004; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Kansas City, 2004-2005; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minneapolis, 1995; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Nashville, 2011, 2013; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Ottawa, 2006; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Philadelphia, 1997-1998; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Philadelphia, 2009-2010; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Pittsburgh, 2002; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - San Antonio, 1999-2000; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Seattle, 2011-2012; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Tampa, 2008; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Toronto, 1996-1997; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Yale, 2001; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Atlanta American Hotel, 1985; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Annual Meeting - Pacific Coast Historians of Education, 1982-1986; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Conference Program, 1971; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1977 (Toronto), 1969-1977; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1979 Meeting, 1977-1978; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1981 (Pittsburgh), 1980-1983; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1983, 1982-1983; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1987 Programs & Planning, Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1988 Program, 1987-1988; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1989 Program/Planning, 1988; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Governance and Society records, 1960-2006; Series 2
  Arranged loosely alphabetical by folder title.
  - Addresses, 2006; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Agenda, Undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Agendas, Undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Agreement between the School of Education, New York University, and the History of Education Society, 1966; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Allen School and House Preservation Corporation, May 1, 1978; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, Undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - American Educational Research Association - Correspondence, 1968; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - American Educational Studies Association, Undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - American Educational Studies Association Survey, Undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - American Educational Studies Association, January, 1983; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - America Historical Association, January 13, 1972; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Announcements for the Network, Undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Annual Meeting Accounts, 1984-1985; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Annual Meeting Accounts, 1985; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Annual Meeting Accounts, 1986; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Annual Meeting Accounts, 1987; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Annual Meeting Accounts, 1988-1989; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Annual Meeting $, 1989; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Annual Report (March 1, 1966-February 28, 1967, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Annual Report (March 1, 1968-February 28, 1969), Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Annual Report (March 1, 1969-February 28, 1970), Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Annual Reports, 1969-1983; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report, 1973-1974; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report, 1977-1981; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports, 1980-1989; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports, 1974-2007; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Application Cover Sheet, 1974-1979; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Archives Committee, 2009-2010; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Archives Correspondence, 1984; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Audit, 2001-2002; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - B. Edward McClellan, 1985-1987; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - B. Edward McClellan Correspondence, 1985-1986; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Ballot, 1983; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Biography, Undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Blackwell Proposal, 2002-2004; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors Agenda, October 17, 1980; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors Meeting in Pittsburgh, 1980-1981; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Pittsburgh Agenda, October 2, 1981; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Portland, Oregon, 1980; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes, October 19, 1984; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes, November, 1985; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes, 1986; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes (includes business meeting), 1987; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Board of Directors/Business Meeting - Minutes, 1988; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes, 1988; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Board of Directors - Reports, 1989-1990; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes, 1989; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Board of Directors - Reports, 1989-1990; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Board of Directors - Minutes, 1989-1990; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Board of Directors - Discussions - Outsourcing Higher Education Quarterly, 2002-2003; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Book Reviews, 1972; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "The Bryn Mawr Workers' Summer School, 1921-1938: A Surprising Alliance", 1983; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Budget for Higher Education Quarterly (September 1, 1966 - August, 1967), Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Capital City Press, 1979-1985; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Columbia University Press, 1982-1983; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Combined Book Exhibit, 1966-1969; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Ad Hoc Committee, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Business Meetings at the annual conference, 1991-2008; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Business Meeting Minutes, 1990-2006; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - The Canadian History of Education Association, October, 1983; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Committee on Academic Standards and Accreditation, Ca. 1986; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Comment on "New York City Schools March Off to War, Undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Comment on "Some Ironies of Jeffersonian Democracy", September 13, 1987; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Comment on "Theory and History of Education in Zimbabwe", Undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Comment on "Who Were the Progressive Educators", September 13, 1987; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Constitution of the History of Education Society, February 11, 1960; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Constitution of the History of Education Society, 1988-1989; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Constitution of the History of Education Society, Undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Constitution of the History of Education Society, Ca. 1980; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Constitution of the History of Education Society, Undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Constitution of the History of Education Society, Undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Constitution of the History of Education Society, Undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Constitution of the History of Education Society, Ca. 1974-1975; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Constitution & Amendments - Old, June, 1984; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Constitution - Current, Ca. 1986; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Coordinating Council for Learned Societies in Education, 1977-1980; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Additional Statement for Mr. Alton Capps Student Appeal, Undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Agenda for Atlanta Meeting of History of Education Society, Undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Alumni Rejections Committee, Undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report, 1978; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Annual Report, 1979; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Associated Organizations for Teacher Edition, January 8, 1973; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Backman's Notes, Undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Biographical Survey, Undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Bobst Library - New York University, October 25, 1978; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Books Received, Fall, 1981; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Books Reviewed, Undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Burgess Publishing Company, October 13, 1966; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Certificate Registration of a Claim to Copyright History of Education Quarterly, 1962-1964; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Columbia University Oral History Research Office, April 27, 1973; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Comments on "Cathedral of Culture: The Schoolhouse in American Educational Thought and Practice Since 1820", Undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Comments on: "Education and the Market Revolution", Undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Comments on: "Rhetoric and Resistance: Social Science and Community Schools for Navajos in the 1930s", Undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Constitution of History of Education Society, February 11, 1960; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence between A. Hunter Dupree and Mr. Berson, April 18, 1982; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence from Alan Dawley to Paul Mattingly, March 16, 1979; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence between Alan H. Jones and members of the Council of Learned Societies in Education, January 3, 1984; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence between Alan H. Jones and members of the Council of Learned Societies in Education, January 20, 1983; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence between Alan Gillespie and Jonathan Messerli, November 24, 1967; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence between Alan H. Jones to Robin K. Berson, March 19, 1984; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence to Alan J. De Young, 1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence between Alan Jones and Devid Ment, 1985, 1988; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence between Alan Jones and Members of the Council of Learned Societies in Education, 1985-1989; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence between Alexandra Birkos and Editor Higher Education Quarterly, 1967; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence between Amy Schutz and David Ment, May 24, 1988; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence from Andre Kuczewski, October 15, 1984; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence between Ann Keppel and Henry Perkinson, 1964, 1967; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence from Alfred Lauterman, March 31, 1979; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence between Alfred Lauterman and Mr. Berson, September 21, 1979; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence between Allan Horlick and Karen M. Offen, February 13, 1974; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence between Annette Duggan and Mr. Berson, May 28, 1980; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence between Allan S. Horlick and Professor Robert Church, January 22, 1976; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence between Allan S. Horlick and Professor Thomas A. Rhodes, 1974; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence between Allan Stanley Horlick and Professor Thomas Flagg, May 23, 1973; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence between Allan Horlick and Wayne Urban, 1973-1974; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence between Allan S. Horlick and Ms. Ann Hyde, October 3, 1974; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence between Allan S. Horlick and Senior Vice President, February 5, 1974; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence between Allan Stanley and Ms. Gillian Schofer, September, 1974; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence between Allan S. Stanley and Professor W. Dougherty, September 12, 1974; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence between Alton Horsnby and Robin Berson, December 5, 1980; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence to Amy Schutt, 1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence between Amy Schutt and Charles W. Turnbull, 1985; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence between Amy Schutt and Katherine De Lawter, 1985; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence between Amy Schutt and the Faxon Company, 1985; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence between Anna Maria Castro and Roberto Wein, June 28, 1973; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence between Annette Duggan and Mr. Mattingly, 1980; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence between Arthur Engel and Robin Berson, February 10, 1982; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence to B. Edward McClellan, April 16, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence to B. Edward McClellan, Undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence to B. Edward McClellan, Undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and David L. Angus, January 12, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and Don T. Martin, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence between B .Edward McClellan and Jennings, August 20, 1985; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and Joseph Harrington, May 20, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and Judith K. Rafferty, June 5, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and Judith K. Rafferty, January 26, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and Lawrence Dennis, `August 13, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and Mary S. Koske, June 10, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan to Mr. Barry H. Bergen, January 26, 1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and Ronald K. Gardenow, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan to Mr. Thomas W. Gutowski, May 29, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and Noel L. Brann, February 17, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and Professor Lynn Gordon, June 26, 1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence between to B. Edward McClellan to William R. Johnson, January 19, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and Professor John Rory, February 26, 1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and Professor Joan Burstyn, August 18, 1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and Professor Patrick J. Harrigan, 1985-1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and Professor Rothblatt, September 12, 1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and Steve Crum, June 11, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and William E. Eaton, June 10, 1988; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and William S. Lewis, August 4, 1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Correspondence between B. Edward McClellan and William L. Lawrence, February 15, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Correspondence between B. K. Hyams and P.H. Mattingly, 1983-1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Correspondence from Barbara Brenzel to Robin Berson, August 20, 1979; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Correspondence between Barbara Heyns and Mr. Mattingly, March 4, 1981; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Correspondence between Barbara Parker and Colleague, September 22, 1983; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Correspondence between Barnett Singer and Paul H. Mattingly, December 26, 1975; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Correspondence between Barry H. Bergen and Carl Kaestle, September 1, 1981; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Correspondence between Barry H. Bergen to Mr. B. Edward McClellan, January 30, 1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Correspondence between Barry Bergen to Ms. Amy C. Scott, March 6, 1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Correspondence between Barry H. Bergen and Ms. Amy C. Schutt, January 20, 1986; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Correspondence between Barry Bergen to Robin Berson, February 8, 1984; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Correspondence between Beatrice Beach Szekely and Clarence J. Karier, June 1, 1978; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Correspondence from Ben Elkof, Undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - Correspondence between Bernard J. Looks and Paul H. Mattingly, February 20, 1973; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - Correspondence between Bernard J. Looks and Paul H. Mattingly, November 25, 1972; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Correspondence between Bernice M. Fisher and Jurgen Herbst, 1979; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - Correspondence between Betsy Schmidt and Paul Mattingly, March 6, 1975; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - Correspondence to Bill, Undated; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 93)
  - Correspondence between Bill Reese and Larry Cuban, 1987; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 94)
  - Correspondence between Bill Weber and Paul H. Mattingly, February 19, 1973; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - Correspondence between Board of Directors of the History of Education Society and Clarence J. Karier, February 20, 1978; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - Correspondence between Board of Directors and Clarence J. Kanier, February 20, 1978; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 97)
  - Correspondence between Board of Directors and Paul H. Mattingly, 1980-1982; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - Correspondence between Brian Simon and Carl Kaestle, 1980; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - Correspondence between Bruce A. Kimball, Nathan Glazer, and Joseph L. Featherstone, 1981; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 100)
  - Correspondence between Alan H. Jones and Members of the Council of Learned Societies in Education, 1983; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence between Aligarh Muslim University, Allied Publishers Subscription Agency and Higher Education Quarterly, 1980-1983; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence between B. Paine and Paul Mattingly, June 25, 1973; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence between Barbara Finkelstein and Carl Kaestle, October, 1980; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence between Barbara Finkelstein and Professor Sol Cohen, March 4, 1982; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence between Barbara Sicherman and Professor Geraldine Joncich Clifford, October 6, 1976; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence between, 1; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence between, 1; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 8)